Mai Hung Vu

Melbourne, Victoria M: 0401 070 232

Hung.vm2574@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mai-hung-vu-565b1bb2/ https://github.com/herohung093

hectorvu.me

Career Objective

Talented and experienced Software Engineer in web and mobile application development, enterprise software and development cycle optimisation. With a can-do attitude and enthusiasm towards learning new technologies, I'm able to carry out challenging technical tasks. Through University and side projects, I have developed the ability to learn new concepts and technologies quickly and be able to apply those on projects.

Key Skills Summary

Programing languages: JavaScript, Java, Kotlin, Python, C++, Scala, C#.

Operating systems: Windows Server, Centos, Android.

Backend: Spring (MVP, Security), Spring Boot. Relational Databases,

SQL and ORM technologies (JPA2, Hibernate), RESTful APIs. AWS (S3, EC2, Load Balancing, CodeBuild, Code Deploy,

CloudFormation)

Frontend: React.JS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Android (MVP, MVVM, Dagger

2, RxJava), Web Services.

Methodologies: Agile (Jira), SDLC.

Education

Professional Year Program

Feb 2019 - Present

Performance Education, Melbourne

Key Subjects: Australian Business Culture, Environment and Workplace Skills, Professional Business Communication.

Master Spring & Hibernate

April 2018 – Oct 2018

Udemy, Melbourne

React – The Complete Guide (include Hooks, React Router, Redux)

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

Udemv. Melbourne

Bachelor of Information Technology

Mar 2016 - Dec 2018

La Trobe University, Melbourne, Australia

Achievements – Course WAM 80%. Recognised as top 15% of high achievement students worldwide by The Golden Key Club.

Academic Projects

Corporate insights App

Aug 2018 - Sep 2018

La Trobe University, Melbourne

Objective: This project focus was to enable current and prospective investors to make the most

of the eXtensible Business Reporting Language (XBRL) data submitted to regulators, in real time. The application was to pull the most current information, calculate and visualize several useful and relevant ratios and indicators in a visually

easy to grasp way.

Tools: Spring boot for back-end server, PostgreSQL as a database. The application is

deployed on Heroku, the application is available on both IOS and Android. The

project you Agile as a project management methodology.

Duties: As part of a team of 4. I took part in designing, developing, testing application

architecture and user interface on android version. Besides, I also developed APIs

on the server side.

Result: My team and I were selected to bring our product to the La Trobe University 26th

Engineering, Data Science and Information Technology Showcase as our team won

the prize of outstanding implementation.

Employment History

Android Developer Feb 2018 – Nov 2018 Hixel, Melbourne

- Design and build advanced applications for the Android platform.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.
- Work with outside data sources and APIs.
- Unit-test code for robustness, including edge cases, usability, and general reliability
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximise development efficiency.
- Work on Android model such as MVVM, MVP and libraries namely RxJava, Dagger 2, MPAndroid Chart.

Java & React Developer Dragon Dental Ltd,

Nov 2018 - Dec 2019

- Design, implement and maintain Java back-end, and React front-end application phases.
- To take part in software and architectural development activities.
- Conduct software analysis, programming back-end application using Spring Boot, JDBC and Hibernate, testing and debugging.
- Transforming requirements into stipulations.
- Develop, test, implement and maintain application software.
- Recommend changes to improve established Java application processes.
- Develop technical designs for application development.

Front-end Developer Rotageek Ltd, Melbourne

Dec 2019 - Present

- Work with agile teams to deploy and trouble-shoot cloud services (AWS), application deployments into the cloud and application automation in lower levels as well as production
- Participate in solution concepts, capacity planning and design artefacts as a part of project team.
- Undertake front-end challenges and development work.
- Perform code reviews within the team.
- Contribute and workshop product solutions and ideas with the team.
- Design and write AWS Cloud Formation template to create CI/CD pipeline.

Personal Attributes

- Excellent in brainstorming and analysing skills, as proved when I worked as mobile application developer (designing UI and apply technical skills to fulfil requirements).
- Great communication as I have 2 years' experience as a supervisor in hospitality industry.

Hobbies and Interest

Sport: Soccer and gym. Would love to go the gym after a long hard work or and enjoy a weekend soccer match with my team.

Movies: I'm a big fan of Peaky Blinders and Game of Thrones.